[Music]
hi I'm Charlie Duffy for the jeux hatu
series on interior surfaces painting
your ceilings can make a huge
Improvement to the appearance of your
home check out how fabulous this room
looks we're going to show you how we got
it looking like this you might think
that painting a ceiling is a little
daunting but as you'll see it's really
not hard before you begin put your drop
sheets down then grab your ladder brush
tape roller extension pole and tray
start by removing cobwebs with a
broom then wash the ceiling down with
sugar soap using a sponge mop and bucket
you may think you'd be okay to skip
cleaning the ceiling but it's a really
important part of painting to make
things easier set up some flood lights
below so you can see where you've
already painted now tape around your
cornices and edges and also any down
lights you may have we'll be using duux
ceiling white today the first step is
cutting in using a brush paint carefully
along the edges cornices and corners of
the room to create a border around the
ceiling don't forget to go around any
down lights hanging lights or
skylights now that's all done you're
ready to
roll start in one corner and use the
roller in smooth parallel
actions work in roughly 1 square met
areas at a time moving across and then
down working in small areas will also
make make it easier to maintain a wet
Edge once youve finished a large area
you can lay off the paint this is the
most important step in rolling and
prevent streaky lines in your finish
start with your roller not loaded with
paint and rest it in the top left hand
corner gently pull the roller along the
ceiling towards you in one long stroke
then take the roller off and place it
slightly overlapping the original Roll
and Roll Along the ceiling again so
you'll be making making a line on one
side then rubbing it out with each new
roll it's really important not to push
the roller as this creates pressure that
can cause streaks in your paint if
you're doing two coats let the first
coat dry then repeat the process from
the cut in stage we're all done but
we'll leave you with a couple of Handy
tips one thing that can be confusing is
painting white onto an already white
ceiling use duux never miss which goes
on pink and dries white and if you're
painting your ceing in your kitchen or
bathroom use duux wash and wear kitchen
and bathroom ceiling this will prevent
mold and bacteria from growing on the
surface this looks great there is a huge
difference from where we've started
thanks for your help Drew no worries
Charlie worth doing worth Jex
[Music]